<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Devi&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Devi&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 23:20:44 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://devi-a.com/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>So Many Releases, So Little Time</title>
      <link>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/so-many-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 23:20:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/so-many-releases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since my last update&amp;mdash;time spent redesigning my website, making a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; blog, and of course working on games! And after some hard work, I&amp;rsquo;m proud to announce the release of two of those games today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;FUSION GALAXY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/umY061u91Dw&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.massdigi.org/&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;MassDiGI&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; Summer Innovation Program was where I got my first real start in developing games with a team, and after a summer of work in SIP and another summer of polish, I&amp;rsquo;m proud to announce the release of Fusion Galaxy&amp;mdash;a fast-paced mobile game. Travel around the universe to collect elements, craft them together, and try to unlock the secret to creating life itself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/fusion-galaxy/id999077925?ls=1&amp;mt=8&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;Get it on iOS&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.massdigi.crafting&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;Get it on Google Play&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;ETERNAL FLOPNATION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.devi-a.com/blog/images/eternal-flopnation.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After SIP, what was there to do but make more games? Over the last few months I worked with a few other SIP alums to finish up a game they were making, which has just been released for mobile. In Eternal Flopnation, try to flop your way to the top of the ocean while avoiding dangerous obstacles like crabs and birds. Hope you have as much fun playing as I did working on this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/eternal-flopnation/id1029639968?mt=8&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;Get it on iOS&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.PD.FishGame&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;Get it on Google Play&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release the Robots!</title>
      <link>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/release-the-robots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 23:20:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/release-the-robots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.devi-a.com/blog/images/rs-banner.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting ready for the weekend? Looking for something to do? Look no further! You can now play Red Survivor, a game me and the folks at Mustachio Games have been working on for a long time! It&amp;rsquo;s now available for FREE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red Survivor is a survival-strategy game for PC and Mac. You get to kill robots, build traps, and keep the flame of humanity alive. So what are you waiting for? Go check it out!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mustachiogames.itch.io/red-survivor&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Play now!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting... Dusk to Dawn!</title>
      <link>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/presenting-dusk-to-dawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 23:20:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/presenting-dusk-to-dawn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on improving my After Effects skills (a tough challenge, I know!) and finally have something to show for my foray into the 3D After Effects environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/158540886&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Fiction Programs Compiled</title>
      <link>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/interactive-fiction-programs-compiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 23:20:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/interactive-fiction-programs-compiled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So recently I started up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/gamewriters/&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;Facebook group&lt;/a&gt; for those interested in writing in game development, as a space for writers to meet others with the same interest and to collaborate with other game devs on narrative games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the group, I&amp;rsquo;m writing up a series of documents about helpful tools and strategies for choice-based writing, and figured I should post a link to them here as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin&amp;mdash;the best of interactive fiction programs to get you started on your way to writing interactive stories.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1IJZOKB_wYJ_7fZGrnPRjHDXkXQgqRkib_IfW3KedGIY/pub?embedded=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPT IN: An Interactive Film</title>
      <link>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/opt-in-an-interactive-film/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 23:20:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/opt-in-an-interactive-film/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;854&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen src=&#34;https://v.interlude.fm/embed/MbZd1M?publisherID=V3a6Jf&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last semester I spent one class studying how digital media affects our society. We talked about all sorts of topics, from postmodernism to digital aesthetics to cyber sex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a final project, I researched and created a video using &lt;a href=&#34;https://interlude.fm/&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;Interlude&lt;/a&gt;, a site that allows users to create interactive videos. I&amp;rsquo;m not one to pass up an opportunity to employ transmedia madness, and so here it is&amp;mdash;OPT IN, an interactive project featuring the voice of &lt;a href=&#34;http://isaiahmann.com/&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;Isaiah Mann&lt;/a&gt; and plenty of footage lovingly sourced from &lt;a href=https://archive.org/ target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;Archive.org&lt;/a&gt;. The video discusses privacy and data tracking in the digital age, and provides the names of tools that can be used to protect one&amp;rsquo;s privacy going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A POSTMORTEM&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I doubt this will change as I go on, but I wish I had more time to work on this project. As I began to think about what I wanted for the video, I had some stretch goals&amp;ndash;some of which made it in, and others that didn&amp;rsquo;t quite pan out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were to remake this, I would definitely spend more time making my own animations and incorporating more choice-based interaction with the viewer (especially making those choices more meaningful to users).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.devi-a.com/blog/images/treehouse-editor.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these limitations were due to the video program itself&amp;ndash;I spent a  few hours trying to fix a generic error that didn&amp;rsquo;t allow be to export, and the website could be a bit funky on a high-resolution screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website also (as far as I can tell) only allows the maker to give the viewer one set of choices per video, which to me made the whole thing a bit more unwieldy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m glad I got a chance to dip my toes into the interactive video domain, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to trying out this (and other programs I find) again soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathfinding: Stella</title>
      <link>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/pathfinding-stella/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 23:40:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/pathfinding-stella/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a continuation of my previous post, discussing my first Dungeons and Dragons characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the point of a servant to the goddess of wartime and soldiers in a continent of peace? Stella wondered this every day, working in the dark of the Dwarven city in service of Myketa to practice the traditional rites, say the prayers, and treat the bodies of the dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She began her service to Myketa from a young age, apprenticed to a wandering cleric by a family too poor to take care of her own education and training. From her mentor she learned the traditions that she would follow the rest of her life&amp;ndash;the skills of healing the living and performing last rites on the fallen. Although she performed the tasks well, her faith at times wavered&amp;ndash;not her faith in her Goddess, but the faith that her mentor had always upheld in the force of Good in the world. Stella channeled the forces of positive energy in her magic, but had seen too much of death and evil to believe in the purity and strength of goodness alone. Instead she stuck to her wits to guide her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many followers of Myketa, she traveled from place to place, caring for the dead and consoling those left behind, practicing some healing for small sums. She rarely found other servants of Myketa, and when she did exchanged only a few words. Although she served her Goddess dutifully, she couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but feel there was something missing in her life&amp;ndash;she was supposed to protect this nation in a time of war, and yet no war had graced Marion&amp;rsquo;s borders for decades. She of course did not wish for war amongst her people, but could not help but wonder if there was more to her life than this repetition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dwarven city was the place that she had stayed the longest on her travels, the place that she could nearly call home. She found comfort in the dark of the underground, invested herself in her work. It was only when a band of loud-talking adventurers arrived that the city saw the greatest destruction that it had ever yet seen&amp;ndash;an army of invaders, a ferocious dragon, a slaughtered king. This was war, and for once Stella felt that her world had purpose once more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the battle the travelers came to her seeking to bury one of their companions. From hearing their stories, it seemed that wherever these travelers went a trail of destruction followed. It seemed that in this group she would be able to finally fulfill her service to Myketa, helping those she meets to deal with the forces tearing the nation apart. Although she wanted to stay behind to help her fellow followers in their rites to the dead soldiers, she knew that she would have only one chance at adventure. She bid farewell to her past and joined these adventurers on their quest to unravel the mysteries of the darkness plaguing Marion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stella was slow to find her place in the unfamiliar group but found fun in life drinking and partying in the downtime of her journeys. It was the adventuring part that she was less comfortable with. She had seen many a dead body before, but this was a whole new beast&amp;ndash;a world where she had to kill or be killed. She had never before seen friends get burnt to ash or disemboweled, she had never been kidnapped or transported to another plane. And yet with this new group it seemed it was calamity after calamity. Needless to say, she spent much of the time scared out of her wits, wondering whether to run, knowing that there was little she could to but look on and pray that all would resolve itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where is Stella now? It could be that she&amp;rsquo;s continuing the quest with her companions, finding the source of the strange happenings in Marion. Then again, perhaps she has had enough of near-death experiences, and has decided to settle down, even if only for a while. Either way, there is sure to be many an adventure in her future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathfinding: Boris</title>
      <link>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/pathfinding-boris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 23:20:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/pathfinding-boris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the summer I had two plans: I wanted to learn how to play Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons and Magic: The Gathering. Needless to say it was a great summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I recount my first characters, played in D&amp;amp;D Pathfinder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;BORIS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first character, Boris, was a halfling who used to live alone on the border between the woods and the fields at the foot of the mighty Dwarven city. He hunted down animals and the magical beasts he found, trading both animal parts and wool from the sheep he tended to. But restlessness stirred Boris into something resembling action, and he left behind the little he owned in search of something to soothe his sudden wanderlust. His travels brought him to a small town not renowned for much but a local magician.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was there, amidst the quiet bustle of the village, that Boris felt he could speak for the first time in what seemed a lifetime. He had assumed that his isolation, his reservation, it had been a choice, it had been what he wanted, and yet now that he found himself among others he could not keep from clinging to the life around him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the first of those connections, the one he valued until the end, was that of the bartender of the town, a brash and sarcastic man whose conversation hinted that he&amp;rsquo;d seen far more than any ordinary village bartender. As soon as Boris saw the bartender he knew it was love, not in the cerebral sense, but in the way that he suddenly could not imagine what his life would be like without this man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boris tried to carry on some halting, painful conversation, but was far too ill-equipped for any such talk. He left in the morning, heard talk of a call for adventurers to investigate the strange behavior of the ley lines nearby. Adventuring&amp;hellip; that seemed a good way to find companionship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boris warmed a little to his traveling companions. He was not much of a fighter, good with a bow and slipping out of tight spaces. But he had lived the life of the ordinary&amp;ndash;and it was here that he saw sights that made him freeze in his tracks. Strange spiders that would swarm and left dead bodies in their wake. Feral wolves with teeth falling out and regrowing. Rifts in the once-peaceful land of Marion. He could put on a brave face in combat and vanquish his foes, but it only heightened his sense that there was something very wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as the party returned to the village, he saw that it was burning. Those who he had found solace with just the day before were now driven to insanity, attacking Boris and each other. Again, Boris quietly readied his bow, and put in end to the villagers&amp;rsquo; suffering, not knowing what else he could possibly do, hoping it would all end soon. They fought their way to the local magician, the one who had originally posted the call for the quest, only to find a grotesque sight&amp;ndash;the magician&amp;rsquo;s stiff corpse, floating by some unholy means, somehow uttering a strange chant. The paladin, who Boris quickly discovered had a penchant for the strange and disgusting, began to sever the limbs of the corpse one by one, until all that was left was a floating, lifeless heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boris did not know what to do, and so he followed his instincts. When he saw the bartender had survived and was on his way to the nation&amp;rsquo;s capitol, Boris went right up to that man, went down on one knee, and proposed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As anyone else could have expected, anyone but the foolhardy Boris, the bartender laughed off the ridiculous proposal and went on his way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And once again, Boris felt any happiness he had slipping from his grasp. What could he do to reclaim the hope that he cherished, if only for a moment? He went back to this new band of adventurers, decided that love could be found, that it was out there somewhere. And so he set off to find it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout his journey Boris had many sorry attempts at flirting, befriending, and joking. He narrowly skirted death on many an occasion. He both feared and loved the strange and dangerous world around him, both cherished and rejected his companions. He made this wayward wandering into life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was at the Dwarven city that had always overshadowed his tiny home that Boris finally met a force he could not conquer. Armies besieged the city, flooding through the gates, pushing back the forces of unity that held the empire together. Just as the enemy waves seemed to wane, a dragon crashed through the stone ceiling with a deathly roar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The heroes rushed to the parapets, tried to take down the dragon by fumbling with the system of catapults and ballistas there. The Dwarven king seemed prepared for this instance, through enchantments growing him to far beyond his normal size, and he faced off against the winged beast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The battle was slow, grueling. The forces of justice were slowly being slaughtered, and although Boris did his best to fight he could feel his strength fading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dragon whittled down the king&amp;rsquo;s strength before finishing him off with a killing blow. With a flap of his leathery wings he descended upon the adventurers, letting loose a gout of flame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Burnt and bleeding, Boris&amp;rsquo;s body gave out. Although he never did find the love that he sought, he lived a life full of adventure, far more than he had ever expected to see in his short life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks for the awesome group at MassDiGI&amp;rsquo;s Summer Innovation Program for making this happen!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>