<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twine on Devi&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://devi-a.com/blog/tags/twine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twine on Devi&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 23:20:44 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://devi-a.com/blog/tags/twine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Fiction Programs Compiled</title>
      <link>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/interactive-fiction-programs-compiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 23:20:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/interactive-fiction-programs-compiled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So recently I started up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/gamewriters/&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;Facebook group&lt;/a&gt; for those interested in writing in game development, as a space for writers to meet others with the same interest and to collaborate with other game devs on narrative games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the group, I&amp;rsquo;m writing up a series of documents about helpful tools and strategies for choice-based writing, and figured I should post a link to them here as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin&amp;mdash;the best of interactive fiction programs to get you started on your way to writing interactive stories.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1IJZOKB_wYJ_7fZGrnPRjHDXkXQgqRkib_IfW3KedGIY/pub?embedded=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPT IN: An Interactive Film</title>
      <link>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/opt-in-an-interactive-film/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 23:20:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://devi-a.com/blog/post/opt-in-an-interactive-film/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;854&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen src=&#34;https://v.interlude.fm/embed/MbZd1M?publisherID=V3a6Jf&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last semester I spent one class studying how digital media affects our society. We talked about all sorts of topics, from postmodernism to digital aesthetics to cyber sex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a final project, I researched and created a video using &lt;a href=&#34;https://interlude.fm/&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;Interlude&lt;/a&gt;, a site that allows users to create interactive videos. I&amp;rsquo;m not one to pass up an opportunity to employ transmedia madness, and so here it is&amp;mdash;OPT IN, an interactive project featuring the voice of &lt;a href=&#34;http://isaiahmann.com/&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;Isaiah Mann&lt;/a&gt; and plenty of footage lovingly sourced from &lt;a href=https://archive.org/ target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt;Archive.org&lt;/a&gt;. The video discusses privacy and data tracking in the digital age, and provides the names of tools that can be used to protect one&amp;rsquo;s privacy going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A POSTMORTEM&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I doubt this will change as I go on, but I wish I had more time to work on this project. As I began to think about what I wanted for the video, I had some stretch goals&amp;ndash;some of which made it in, and others that didn&amp;rsquo;t quite pan out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were to remake this, I would definitely spend more time making my own animations and incorporating more choice-based interaction with the viewer (especially making those choices more meaningful to users).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.devi-a.com/blog/images/treehouse-editor.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these limitations were due to the video program itself&amp;ndash;I spent a  few hours trying to fix a generic error that didn&amp;rsquo;t allow be to export, and the website could be a bit funky on a high-resolution screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website also (as far as I can tell) only allows the maker to give the viewer one set of choices per video, which to me made the whole thing a bit more unwieldy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m glad I got a chance to dip my toes into the interactive video domain, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to trying out this (and other programs I find) again soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>